Dom Alexander (Dom, he/him)

Denver, CO | 210-837-0670 | dom.alexan@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Motivated, disciplined, and armed with ruthless persistence, I am a software developer cutting my teeth on tech as it goes forward towards an ever-expanding horizon. Experienced with full-stack development using languages such as HTML, CSS, JS, TS, React, Ruby on Rails, and C#. In the spirit of always pursuing knowledge, I am currently furthering my knowledge with C#--heading towards Unity--and MongoDB. A performance-driven problem solver, I am dedicated to helping your team realise its goals in the most efficient and functional ways possible.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Coding Languages & Frameworks: HTML, CSS, JS, TS, MERN, Ruby on Rails, C#

Currently learning: C, MongoDB

Other Technologies: VS Code, Git, GitHub, Postman, Wordpress, Microsoft Office (all suites), Adobe

Creative Suite (Premiere Pro, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Dreamweaver), PostgreSQL

Other Skills: Copywriting, Editing, ESL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

KP2020JOBS - Github | Private Production

A utility that runs via task scheduler at regular intervals to export orders and import various files from Kaiser Permanente.

- → Custom C# ETL processes for exchanging data to support contact lens ordering Currently:
 - Upgrading custom logging to standard logging framework
 - General refactoring to implement best practices
 - Upgrading to .NET6

Cropsey - Github | Demo

• A simple responsive app (React + Rails) to showcase the NY-based band Cropsey

The Black Vinyl Market - Github | Currently in Development

A full-stack (C# + .NET6 + Blazor) app dedicated to user-to-user sales & purchasing of alternative vinyls/records.

- Ongoing development. Next feature: user authentication && cart functionality
- Set up routes in accordance to C#/Blazor best practices
- Practised isolated CSS in accordance to Blazor standards

EXPERIENCE

Coding For Hermit Crabs

Software Engineer Apprentice

Denver, Colorado (Remote) 03/2023 - Present

- Developing an ever-expanding base curriculum of HTML, CSS, and JS + React for novice students beginning to learn to program
- Collaborating with other interns on projects intended to showcase the capabilities of basic apps written in HTML, CSS, and React

Bacon Social House LLC

Bartender

Denver, Colorado 04/2021 - 07/2022

- Collaborated with all front of house staff to provide excellent service to guests while averaging a \$25+ PPA
- Managed bar prep, inventory, and cash drawers
- Conducted proficient sales transactions using Aloha & Toast POS

<u>Freelance</u>

Editor & English Teacher

- Negotiated individual learning goals to be able to guide students towards a productive, personalised, and realised outcome
- Crafted curriculum for classes of 20-30 students with ages ranging from young adult (12+), adult (18+), and seniors (60+)
- Initiated study groups for students who intended to take the IELTS, resulting in band scores of an average of 7.5-9 per student

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Denver, Colorado 10/ 2022 - 02/2023

University of Colorado - DenverDenver, ColoradoBachelors of Arts - English (Literature) (Incomplete/Pending)08/2020 - 10/2022

Northwest Vista CollegeSan Antonio, TexasAssociates of Arts - English06/2015 - 12/2017

University of Adelaide, Cambridge University

Certificate in Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages

Adelaide, South Australia 01/2018